nationalservice.gov 2009-12-31

# NationalService.gov > Security and Privacy Policy

### Disclaimer 

Some of the documents on this server may contain live references (or pointers) to information created and maintained by other organizations. Please note that the Corporation does not control and cannot guarantee the relevance, timeliness, or accuracy of these outside materials. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that website. 

Except for the AmeriCorps recruitment profiles and application, the Record of Service, this website and the information it contains are considered public information, are provided as a public service by the Corporation for National and Community Service (Corporation), and may be distributed or copied. This system is monitored to ensure proper operation, to verify the functioning of applicable security features, and for other like purposes. 

Thank you for visiting the Corporation's website. This policy explains how the Corporation will handle information we learn about you from your visit to our website. 

### Browsing or Downloading

If you browse through our site or download information, we automatically collect and temporarily store the following anonymous information about your visit: 1) the name of the domain from which you access the Internet; 2) the date and time you access our site; and 3) the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site. We use this information for statistical purposes and to help us make our site more useful to visitors. Unless it is specifically stated otherwise, no additional information will be collected about you. We do not disclose, give, sell or transfer any personal information we receive to any outside parties, unless required for law enforcement or statute. 

### Use of Cookies

Sometimes we use "session cookies," which are small amounts of information stored on your computer to secure the connection during your visit. After you turn off your computer or stop using the internet, the cookies are erased. 

### Privacy Impact Assessments

Privacy Impact Assessments (PIAs) have been completed for the CNCS general support system and all major applications. 

The Corporation collects and maintains a limited amount of personally identifiable information from applications for Corporation national and community service programs. This information is used to process the application and subsequently manage and support service participants. The process for collecting and maintaining personally identifiable information within the Corporation’s Network, Momentum, ACRPS, ESPAN, and LASSIE information systems meets the requirements set by OMB Memorandum 03-22.* 

To obtain a copy of a PIA for an information system, please contact: 

Mary Cadagin  
Chief Information Officer and Senior Agency Official for Privacy  
Corporation for National and Community Service  
1201 New York Avenue, NW  
Washington DC 20525

* Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is defined by OMB as any information about an individual maintained by an agency, including, but not limited to, education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history and information which can be used to distinguish or trace an individual's identity, such as their name, social security number, date and place of birth, mother’s maiden name, biometric records, etc., including any other personal information which is linked or linkable to an individual.

### Sending Us an E-mail

If you decide to send us personally identifying information, such as in an e-mail, that information may be subject to disclosure. It will be handled in accordance with the Privacy Act and the Freedom of Information Act, which restrict our use of it, yet permits certain disclosures. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact us at: 

Corporation for National and Community Service  
1201 New York Ave., NW  
Washington DC 20525  
202-606-5000  

### Information Security, Privacy and Contractor Security Requirements

The Federal Information Security Act (FISMA), Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12 (HSPD-12), and recent OMB Memorandums instituted a number of security and privacy requirements that must be reflected in all federal contracts. Recent changes to the FAR provided guidance as to how to include information security and privacy requirements in contracts for information technology components and services, information and data management services, and related support. 

Our recent FISMA system security assessments confirmed that all current Corporation information technology contracts as well as contracts where contractors are provided access to CNCS IT systems or facilities require modification to include consideration for FISMA, HSPD-12, and OMB security requirements. To assist current and potential contractors and vendors, CNCS is making its information, privacy, and contractor security requirements available at <http://www.nationalservice.gov/pdf/infosec_contract_clauses.pdf>.

* * *

### AmeriCorps Alumni Profile Card (AmeriCorps eCommunity)

PUBLIC BURDEN STATEMENT: The Agency informs the potential person who is to respond to the collection of information that such person is not required to respond to the collection of information unless it displays a currently valid OMB Control Number. Any Comments regarding this collection of information send to: (See 5 C.F.R. 1320.5(b)(2)(i).) 

PRIVACY ACT NOTICE: The Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C § 552a) requires that the following notice be provided to you: The authority for collecting information from you in this application is contained in 42 U.S.C 12592 and 12615 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 as amended, and 42 U.S.C. 4953 of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 as amended. The purpose of the card is to enhance communication between the Corporation for National and Community Service (Hereinafter "CNCS") and former members to provide them with information on CNCS activities and to seek their assistance in volunteer recruitment activities. The information must also be used for general routine uses described in 65 FR 46890, providing the information is voluntary. It will not be disclosed outside he government without written permission.

**OMB Control Number:** 3045-0048  
 **Expiration Date:** November 30, 2010

* * *

### AmeriCorps Member Application

PUBLIC BURDEN STATEMENT: Public reporting burden for this collection of information is estimated to average 45 minutes per submission, including reviewing instructions, gathering and maintaining the data needed, and completing the form. Comments on the burden or content of this instrument may be sent to the Corporation for National Service, AmeriCorps Recruitment, Attn: Denise Yeager, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, D.C. 20525. The Corporation informs people who may respond to this collection of information that they are not required to respond to the collection of information unless the OMB control number and expiration date displayed on page 1 are current and valid. (See 5 C.F.R. 1320.5(b)(2)(i).) 

PRIVACY ACT NOTICE: The Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C § 552a) requires that the following notice be provided to you: The authority for collecting information from you in this application is contained in 42 U.S.C 12592 and 12615 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 as amended, and 42 U.S.C. 4953 of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 as amended. You are advised that submission of the information is entirely voluntary, but the requested information is required in order for you to participate in AmeriCorps programs. The principal purpose for requesting this personal information is to process your application for acceptance into an AmeriCorps program, and for other general routine purposes associated with your participation in an AmeriCorps program. These routine purposes may include disclosure of the information to federal, state, or local agencies pursuant to lawfully authorized requests, to present and former employers, references provided by you in your application, and educational institutions, for the purpose of verifying the information provided by you in your application. In some programs, the information may also be provided to federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies to determine the existence of any prior criminal convictions. The information will not otherwise be disclosed to entities outside of AmeriCorps and the Corporation for National Service without your prior written permission.

**OMB Control Number:** 3045-0054  
 **Expiration Date:** January 31, 2009

### Project Registration System

PUBLIC BURDEN STATEMENT: Public reporting burden for this collection of information is estimated to average 20 minutes per submission, including reviewing instructions, gathering and maintaining the data needed, and completing the form. Comments on the burden or content of this instrument may be sent to the Corporation for National Service, AmeriCorps Recruitment, Attn: David Premo, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, D.C. 20525. The Corporation informs people who may respond to this collection of information that they are not required to respond to the collection of information unless the OMB control number and expiration date displayed on page 1 are current and valid. (See 5 C.F.R. 1320.5(b)(2)(i).) 

PRIVACY ACT NOTICE: The Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C § 552a) requires that the following notice be provided to you: The authority for collecting information from you in this application is contained in 42 U.S.C 12592 and 12615 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 as amended, and 42 U.S.C. 4953 of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 as amended. You are advised that submission of the information is entirely voluntary, but the requested information is required in order for you to use the Project Registration System.  The principal purpose for requesting this information is to evaluate the effectiveness, reach, scope and range of national service projects.  The information, at the option of the registrant, may use the site to display information about the project and to recruit volunteers.  The information will be used by Corporation employees, potential volunteers, and volunteer project administrators.  The information will not otherwise be disclosed to entities outside the Corporation for National Service without your prior written permission. 

**OMB Control Number:** 3045-0122  
 **Expiration Date:**  November 30, 2009

* * *

### Record of Service

Your e-mail address is only used because it is the best way for you to sign in with a unique identity that's easy to remember. No e-mail will be sent to you unless you ask for it. We do not share e-mail addresses with third-parties, other than to manage our database.

PUBLIC BURDEN STATEMENT: Public reporting burden for this collection of information is estimated at 3 minutes, which includes the initial log-on, providing initial profile user, recording of volunteer service information, and log-off from the diary. Comments on the burden or content of the instrument may be sent to the Corporation for National and Community Service, Attn: Director, Public Affairs, 1201 New York Avenue, N.W., Washington, D.C., 20525. (5 C.F.R. 1320.5(b)(2)(b)) The Corporation informs the potential persons who wish to respond to the collection of information that such persons are not required to respond to the collection of information unless it displays a currently valid OMB control number which is located on this website. 

PRIVACY ACT NOTICE: The Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C § 552a) requires that the following notice be provided to you: The authority for collecting information from you in this application is contained in 42 U.S.C 12592 and 12615 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 as amended, and 42 U.S.C. 4953 of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 as amended. The primary purpose of the user account is to provide a means that allows individuals to record, track, and provide comment on their volunteer services. Users may also elect to be provided with additional information about other service opportunities. Providing this information is voluntary. All information contained in each user account is available only to the Corporation, on behalf of USA Freedom Corps, and will not be provided to any organization outside the Corporation. 

**OMB Control Number:** 3045-0077  
 **Expiration Date:** February 28, 2009

* * *

### Presidential Freedom Scholarships

The Presidential Freedom Scholarships program has been discontinued.
